# **ALAN HENRY**

# FRONTEND DEVELOPER



### **SKILLS**

#### **TECHNICAL**

NodeJS

JavaScript

**TypeScript** 

Angular

React

**Express** 

Jest

Playwright

Python

MySQL

MongoDB

Redis

Docker Azure

Bicep

**Terraform** 

OpenShift

**OWASP ZAP** 

Keycloak

Git & Github

Linux

Agile

#### **PROFESSIONAL**

Communication

Teamwork

Attentive

Pragmatic

Leadership

## **EDUCATION**

## **BEng (Hons) Automotive Engineering**

University of Huddersfield 2002 - 2006

#### CERTIFICATIONS

### **NETWORK+**

CompTIA Completed: March 2023

#### **AZURE AZ-104**

Microsoft In progress

## **PROFILE**

Self-driven and analytical team player with 13 years of military experience. A diligent individual who thrives on problem-solving and getting the details right while delivering to time and target. Excited for opportunities to be at the forefront of advancements in IT.

# **EXPERIENCE**

### FRONTEND DEVELOPER

With You With Me | 2023 - Present

- Contracted to the Ministry of Defence (MOD).
- Worked as part of an agile team to deliver web applications with a focus on current content, security and accessibility.
- Front end development using TypeScript, NodeJS, Express, and Docker.
- Translated UX and content designs into functional code, leveraging Government and MOD Design Systems to standardise multiple MOD websites.
- Developed a custom-themed and security-hardened Kevcloak instance enabling sensitive content to be hosted on the website.
- Set up Redis for secure session management and tested security using OWASP ZAP, leading to hardened code and successful penetration tests.
- Created unit test using Jest and end-to-end tests using Playwright and to ensure robust and efficient code.
- Used Microsoft Azure Communication Services to create a Python-based custom communications centre app with Interactive Voice Response.
- Used Bicep and Terraform to create IaC configurations for Azure-based apps.
- Authored comprehensive technical documentation and diagrams to detail both code and team processes.
- Employed Git and GitHub for version control, ensuring code integrity and collaboration.
- Set up automated GitHub Actions to pre-emptively identify formatting errors and security issues before deployment to OpenShift.
- Utilised Jira and Confluence for efficient project management and liaised with senior management to plan and execute projects.

### **BRANCH INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY SECURITY OFFICER**

British Army | 2021 - 2023

- Ensured continuous compliance with latest updates and backups, preventing the risk of data loss or theft.
- Maintained records of all workstations and personal electronic devices, ensuring accountability and enhancing overall security measures.

### **TEAM LEADER**

British Army | 2010 - 2023

- Performed as part of a large multi-disciplinary team producing world-class ceremonial music for high-profile military, royal, and charity engagements globally.
- Successfully led and managed multiple teams on time-sensitive projects to achieve high standards of completion.
- Provided first-line incident response within the London Central Garrison to maintain vital security.
- Mentored, trained, and ensured welfare of new employees.

# ADDITIONAL ACTIVITIES

- Army Reservist
- Mountain Bike Instructor
- Freelance musician
- Music composition and arrangement for professional ensembles